Guide to the Stanford University, Plant Services Office, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Plant Services Office, records
1888-1953
1888-1922
SC0123
Stanford University. Plant Services Office.
15 Linear feet
The bulk of this collection consists of building specifications for various campus buildings and some faculty homes. Includes plans and elevations from a number of campus buildings, primarily pre-1917; expense ledgers for construction costs for 1906 and 1922; and scrapbooks of clippings and photographs, 1944-1953, pertaining to campus planning and construction.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
The bulk of this collection consists of building specifications for various campus buildings and some faculty homes. Includes plans and elevations from a number of campus buildings, primarily pre-1917; expense ledgers for construction costs for 1906 and 1922; and scrapbooks of clippings and photographs, 1944-1953, pertaining to campus planning and construction.
Access Terms
Clark, Arthur Bridgman, 1866-1948; Day, Clinton.; Hodges, Charles Edward, 1824-1870.; Palo Alto Stock Farm (Stanford, Calif.); Peninsular Railway.; Shepley, Rutan and Coolidge.; Stanford Bookstore.; Stanford Inn.; Stanford University. Graduate School of Education. Buildings.; Stanford University. Libraries--Buildings.; Stanford University. Museum of Art --Buildings.; Stanford University. Plant Services Office.; Stanford University. School of Engineering --Buildings.; Wing, Charles B.; Photoprints.; Scrapbooks; Universities and colleges--Buildings.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Aerodynamics Lab (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Art Gallery Part 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Art Gallery Part 2 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Assembly Hall and Little Theater (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bacteriology Lab (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Band Stand (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Basketball Pavillion (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bookstore (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Branner Hall (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Cement and Hydraulics Lab (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Chemistry (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Convalescent Home (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cubberley (Box 1, Folder 12a)
  - Durand (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Economizer and Induced Draft Fan (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Encina Hall (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Engineering and Drafting Bldg. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Faculty Club House (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Filtration Plant (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Geology (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Hoover Cottages (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Lagunita Court (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Lagunita Knoll (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Lavatories (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Library (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Los Altos Golf and Country Club (Box 2, Folder 24a)
  - Memorial Church (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Memorial Hall (Box 2, Folder 25a)
  - Men’s Gym (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Military Office (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Mining and Military Office (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Museum (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Pattern Shop (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Physical Education Bldg. (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Physical Lab Bldg. (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Post Office (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Power Plant (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - President’s House (623 Mirada) (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Print Shop (also Press Shop) (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Outer Quad (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Roble Hall (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Ryan Lab (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Schoolhouse (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Seismological Station (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Sequoia Hall (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Sequoia and Encina Halls (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Shop Bldg. (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Stanford Hospital (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Stirling Boiler (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Substation (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Swimming Pools, Womens (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Toyon Hall (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Union Bldg. (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - University Club, San Francisco (Box 3, Folder 50a)
  - Miscellaneous (roads, sewers, steam and arcades) (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Alpha Phi Fraternity (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Chi Psi Fraternity (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Delta Upsilon Fraternity (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Kappa Alpha (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Kappa Kappa Gamma (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Sigma Alpha Epsilon (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Zeta Psi (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Alvarado Row #544 (old #9), A. C. Whitaker residence (Box 4A, Folder 1)
  - Alvarado Row # 582 (old # 18), G. M. Richardson residence (Box 4A, Folder 2)
  - Alvarado Row # 610 (old # 22), [LSJU building] (Box 4A, Folder 3)
  - Alvarado Row # 612-614 (old # 24-26), A. J. Bain residence (Box 4A, Folder 4)
  - Alvarado Row # 634 (old # ?), “House A” (Box 4A, Folder 5)
  - Alvarado Row # 637 (old # 25), C. G. Allen residence (Box 4A, Folder 6)
  - Alvarado Row # 646 (old # ?), K. G. Rendtorff residence (Box 4A, Folder 7)
  - Alvarado Row # 665 (old # )?, G. S. Parks residence (Box 4A, Folder 8)
  - Alvarado Row # 675 (old # 31), W. D. Allen residence (Box 4A, Folder 9)
  - Alvarado Row # ? (old # ?), W. F. Dietrich residence (Box 4A, Folder 10)
  - Alvarado Row # ? (old # 1), gardener’s cottage (Box 4A, Folder 11)
  - Alvarado Row # ? (old # 33), J. C. Almack residence (Box 4A, Folder 12)
  - Cabrillo # 610 (old # 12), E. P. Cubberley residence (Box 4A, Folder 13)
  - Cabrillo # 622 (old # 14), V. L. Kellogg residence (Box 4A, Folder 14)
  - Cabrillo # 653 (old # ?), L. Abrams residence (Box 4A, Folder 15)
  - Cabrillo # 654 (old # ?), H. W. Stuart residence (Box 4A, Folder 16)
  - Cabrillo # 661 (old # ?), S. D. Townley residence (Box 4A, Folder 17)
  - Cabrillo # 668 (old # 24), M. S. Wildman residence (Box 4A, Folder 18)
  - Cooksey Lane # 743 (old # 10), Prof. Brown residence (Box 4A, Folder 19)
  - Coronado Avenue #736, Miss Bunting residence (Box 4A, Folder 20)
  - Dolores # 717 (old # 2), Theta Xi fraternity (Box 4B, Folder 1)
  - Dolores # 735 (old # ?), W. C. Eells residence (Box 4B, Folder 2)
  - Dolores # 747 (old # 7), Prof. Proctor residence (Box 4B, Folder 3)
  - Dolores # 773 (old # 11), F. E. Olmsted residence (Box 4B, Folder 4)
  - Dolores # 774 (old # 12), R. W. Doane residence (Box 4B, Folder 5)
  - Dolores # 730 or 750 (old # 8), P. J. Treat residence (Box 4B, Folder 6)
  - Dolores # 7-- (old # 9), M. L. Ternan residence (Box 4B, Folder 7)
  - El Escarpado # 421, G. W. Dowrie residence (Box 4B, Folder 8)
  - El Escarpado #445, J. Hugh Jackson residence (Box 4B, Folder 9)
  - El Escarpado #4, H. E. Hotchkiss residence (Box 4B, Folder 10)
  - Foothill Rd. # 441, C. Moser residence (Box 4B, Folder 11)
  - Foothill Rd. # 446, R. V. A. Lee residence (Box 4B, Folder 12)
  - Foothill Rd. # 571, J. W. McBain residence (Box 4B, Folder 13)
  - Foothill Rd. # 574, C. W. Jungeblut residence (Box 4B, Folder 14)
  - Foothill Rd. # 586, H. Hoteling residence (Box 4B, Folder 15)
  - Foothill Rd. # 600, M. L. Huggins residence (Box 4B, Folder 16)
  - Gerona Rd. # 548, G. H. Stuart residence (Box 4B, Folder 17)
  - Gerona Rd. # 593 (old #237), E. G. Mears residence (Box 4B, Folder 18)
  - Gerona Rd. # 607 (old #245), W. R. Miles residence (Box 4B, Folder 19)
  - Lasuen # 538 (old # 6), Phi Delta Theta (Box 4C, Folder 1)
  - Lasuen # 557 (old # 11), Beta Theta Pi (Box 4C, Folder 2)
  - Lasuen # 566 (old # 18), Delta Kappa Epsilon (Box 4C, Folder 3)
  - Lasuen # 573 (old # 17), Alpha Phi (Box 4C, Folder 4)
  - Lasuen # 584 (old # 24), Theta Delta Chi (Box 4C, Folder 5)
  - Lasuen # 586 (old # 26), Delta Chi (Box 4C, Folder 6)
  - Lasuen # 610 (old # 30), Pi Beta Phi sorority (Box 4C, Folder 7)
  - Lasuen # 620 (old # 32), Delta Delta Delta sorority (Box 4C, Folder 8)
  - Lasuen # ? (old # 28), Alpha Tau Omega (Box 4C, Folder 9)
  - Lasuen # ? (old # ?), R. L. Templeton house (Box 4C, Folder 10)
  - Lasuen # ? (old # ?), Henline house [not built] (Box 4C, Folder 11)
  - Mayfield # 506 (old # 15), C. F.Tolman, Jr. (Box 4C, Folder 12)
  - Mayfield # 526 (old # 7), W. D. Briggs (Box 4C, Folder 13)
  - Mayfield # 538 (old # 5), D. H. Campbell and R. E. Allardice (Box 4C, Folder 14)
  - Mayfield # 564 (old # 3), Phi Sigma Kappa (old Acacia house) (Box 4C, Folder 15)
  - Mayfield # ? (old # 38), Phi Gamma Delta (Box 4C, Folder 16)
  - Mirada # 623 (old Reservoir Dr. # 1), Mrs. L. H. Hoover (Box 4C, Folder 17)
  - Mirada # 669 (old # 15), G. D. Barnett (Box 4C, Folder 18)
  - Mirada # 678 (old # 10), C. L. Alsberg (Box 4C, Folder 19)
  - Mirada # 684 (old # 12), Alpha Omecron Pi (Box 4C, Folder 20)
  - Mirada # ? (old # 6), E. C. Franklin (Box 4C, Folder 21)
  - Mirada # 2, G. B. Culver [not built] (Box 4C, Folder 22)
  - Mirada # 8, E. K. Strong Jr. (Box 4C, Folder 23)
  - Salvatierra # 513 (old # 1), Madrono Hall (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Salvatierra # 517 (old # 3 & 5), Charles Reining (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Salvatierra # 523 (old # ?), Y. Ichihashi (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Salvatierra # 611 & 613 (old # 31 & 33), “Dwelling house C” (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Salvatierra # 659 (old # ?), F. E. Terman (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Salvatierra # 660 (old # ?), Ruth Lee (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Salvatierra # 667 (old # ?), W. L. Schwartz (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Salvatierra # 3, Weymouth (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Salvatierra (Lot #190), Boynton M. Green (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - San Juan # 541 (old # 1), T. L. Kelley (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - San Juan # 650 (old # 4), Delta Tau Delta (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - San Juan # 663 (old # 7), Solon Shedd (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - San Juan # 675 (old # 9), W. J. Crook (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - San Juan # ? (old # 6), Sigma Nu (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Santa Maria # 792, Mrs. Elizabeth P. Griffing (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Santa Teresa # 418, W. H. Carpenter ? (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Santa Teresa # 462 (old # 2), W. H. Carpenter ? (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Santa Ynez # 713 (old # 423), Gamma Phi Beta (Box 4E, Folder 1)
  - Santa Ynez # 714 (old # 420), Japanese Student Association (Box 4E, Folder 2)
  - Santa Ynez # 723 (old # 505 & 5), Ryan (Box 4E, Folder 3)
  - Santa Ynez # 739 (old # 10 Cabrillo Ave.) (Box 4E, Folder 4)
  - Santa Ynez # 740 (old # 9 Cabrillo Ave.), L. E. Bassett (Box 4E, Folder 5)
  - Santa Ynez # 755 (old # 6 Cabrillo Ave.), H. Fairclough (Box 4E, Folder 6)
  - Santa Ynez # 756 (old # 5 Cabrillo Ave.), O. L. Elliott (Box 4E, Folder 7)
  - Santa Ynez # 767 (old # 4 Cabrillo Ave.), A. B. Clark (Box 4E, Folder 8)
  - Santa Ynez # 770 (old # 1 Cabrillo Ave.), E. G. Martin (Box 4E, Folder 9)
  - Santa Ynez # 774, J. Taylor (Box 4E, Folder 10)
  - Santa Ynez # 775 (old # 2 Cabrillo Ave.), F. MacFarland (Box 4E, Folder 11)
  - Arcades
    - Arcade, Connecting SE and SW buildings. C. E. Hodges (Box 5A, Folder 1)
    - Arcade entrance. Shepley, Rutan, Coolidge (Box 5A, Folder 1)
    - Arcade entrance (main). Shepley, Rutan, Coolidge (Box 5A, Folder 1)
    - Arcades, sway braces for. Commission of Engineers, 1906 [2] (Box 5A, Folder 1)
    - Arcades, quad fire wall [2] (Box 5A, Folder 1)
  - Arches
    - Elevations. Shepley, Rutan, Coolidge [8] (Box 5A, Folder 2)
  - Assay lab
    - Guy rope connection for steel stack of [2] (Box 5A, Folder 3)
  - Assembly Hall
    - Stairway railing and rear exit. Commission of Engineers, 1906 [5] (Box 5A, Folder 4)
  - Athletic facilities
    - Track, bleachers for ¼ mile. R. A. Hudson [3] (Box 5A, Folder 5)
    - Football field, evacuation and elevation plan, 1906 (Box 5A, Folder 5)
    - Training House bleachers [2] (Box 5A, Folder 5)
    - Track, map of Toilet rooms at athletic field Backstop, benches & goal post (Box 5A, Folder 5)
  - Auditorium (proposed?)
    - Plan, cross section. C. E. Hodges [2] (Box 5A, Folder 6)
  - Blacksmith, pipecutting & foundry
    - Elevations, plans, details. C. E. Hodges, 1892 [5] (Box 5A, Folder 7)
    - Plans, sketches, roof trusses. S. Moser, 1908 [8] (Box 5A, Folder 7)
  - Boiler House
    - Floor plans, cross section, elevation of chimney. Shepley, Rutan, Coolidge [5] (Box 5A, Folder 8)
    - Piping arrangement. S. F. Tool Co., 1891 (Box 5A, Folder 8)
    - Trusses. Commission of Engineers, 1906 (Box 5A, Folder 8)
  - Bookstore
    - Plans and elevations. A. B. Clark [4] (Box 5A, Folder 9)
  - Carpenters’ and Plumbers’ Workshop
    - Plan and elevation. C. E. Hodges [2] (Box 5A, Folder 10)
  - Chapel (Class building “K”)
    - Platform & Robing Room. Shepley, Rutan, Coolidge (Box 5A, Folder 11)
  - Chemistry Building, Clinton Day drawings
    - Floor plans, cross sections, elevations [18] (Box 5A, Folder 12)
  - Chemistry Building
    - Ventilation system. J. G. Grannis, 1904 [3] (Box 5A, Folder 13)
  - Chemistry Building, Commission of Engineers drawings, 1906-07
    - Lab heaters and ventilation [2] (Box 5A, Folder 14)
    - SE gable, motor setting and ventilation [4] (Box 5A, Folder 14)
    - Restoration, windows and roof [2] (Box 5A, Folder 14)
    - Front gable detail (Box 5A, Folder 14)
  - Civil, Mechanical & Electrical Engineering (Quad building)
    - Plans, elevations, and cross sections; cast iron columns; and details of iron stairs. C. E. Hodges [16] (Box 5A, Folder 15)
  - Drafting Building
    - Proposed changes [2] (Box 5A, Folder 16)
  - Entrance Gates
    - Plan. C. E. Hodges (Box 5A, Folder 17)
    - Plan, elevation, section. A. Moretti (Box 5A, Folder 17)
  - Fire Truck House
    - Plans, elevatons. C. E. Hodges [3] (Box 5A, Folder 18)
  - Freehand Drawing, Civil Engineering & Geology [small building in Quad]
    - Plans, elevatons. C. E. Hodges (Box 5B, Folder 1)
  - Furniture and fittings
    - Benches (Roble Hall). S. M. 1908 (Box 5B, Folder 2)
    - Table, women’s rest room. S. M. 1908 (Box 5B, Folder 2)
    - Doors (various Quad buildings). S. M. 1908 (Box 5B, Folder 2)
    - Door and windows, mechanician shop. 1908 (Box 5B, Folder 2)
    - Finial. Commission of Engineers, 1906 (Box 5B, Folder 2)
  - Geology Corner
    - Sections and elevations. C. E. Hodges [12] (Box 5B, Folder 3)
  - Geology Corner
    - Plans. C. E. Hodges [13] (Box 5B, Folder 4)
    - Plan, one-story building. C. E. Hodges [2] (Box 5B, Folder 4)
  - Geology Corner
    - Details for door, stage. S. M. Baker [2] (Box 5B, Folder 5)
  - Gymnasium, Boy’s
    - Elevations, heating and plumbing. Shepley, Rutan & Coolidge [3] (Box 5B, Folder 6)
  - History & English
    - Plans. Commission of Engineers, 1907 [3] (Box 5B, Folder 7)
    - Area steps. C. E.Hodges (Box 5B, Folder 7)
  - Hydraulic Laboratory
    - Plans, elevations, details. H. H. Soult, 1912 [10] (Box 5B, Folder 8)
  - Lampposts, Quad [3] (Box 5B, Folder 9)
  - Library, details
    - Elevators. Commission of Engineers, 1906 [5] (Box 5B, Folder 10)
    - Stairway, catalog room. Commission of Engineers, 1906 [4] (Box 5B, Folder 10)
    - Moulding at dome. Commission of Engineers, 1907 (Box 5B, Folder 10)
    - Doors. Commission of Engineers, 1906 (Box 5B, Folder 10)
  - Library, fire-proofing
    - Roof plans and details. Commission of Engineers, 1907-08 (Box 5B, Folder 11)
  - Library, roof
    - Erection diagrams and deails. Pacific Rolling Mill Co., 1908 [16] (Box 5B, Folder 12)
  - Machine Shop
    - Plans and elevations. C. E. Hodges [8] (Box 5B, Folder 13)
    - Plans, elevations and details. Commission of Engineers, 1907-08 [4] (Box 5B, Folder 13)
  - Mausoleum
    - Elevation and detail of moulding. Shepley, Rutan & Coolidge (Box 5B, Folder 14)
    - Planting plan. F. L. Olmsted & Co., 1890 (Box 5B, Folder 14)
    - Grading plan. F. L. Olmsted & Co., 1888 (Box 5B, Folder 14)
  - Mausoleum (proposed)
    - Plans, elevations, sections. Wm. A. Potter [10] (Box 5B, Folder 15)
  - Mechanical Engineering
    - Foundations for various engines [3] (Box 5C, Folder 1)
    - Foundations for various engines [3] (Box 5C, Folder 1)
    - Foundation plans for engines, 1902 [2] (Box 5B, Folder 1)
    - Sketch plans, 1902 [2] (Box 5B, Folder 1)
    - Sketch plans, 1902 [2] (Box 5B, Folder 1)
  - Medical Department (San Francisco)
    - Details for equipment, desks, and lockers [6] (Box 5C, Folder 2)
  - Memorial Arch
    - Plans and elevations. Shepley, Rutan & Coolidge, revised by C. E. Hodges [10] (Box 5C, Folder 3)
    - Granite cub elevation. C. Moser, Comm. Of Engineers, 1906 (Box 5C, Folder 3)
  - Memorial Church
    - Elevations. Clinton Day [4] (Box 5C, Folder 4)
    - Roof sheating. Commission of Engineers, 1906 (Box 5C, Folder 4)
    - Elevations and plan. Meyers and Ward, 1909 [6] (Box 5C, Folder 4)
  - Metallurgy Lab
    - Plan and comparative bids. S. Moser, 1907 [2] (Box 5C, Folder 5)
    - Plan of walls. C. M., 1907 (Box 5C, Folder 5)
    - Roof truss plans. Berkeley Steel Co., 1907 [7] (Box 5C, Folder 5)
    - Plans and details re roof, foundation & windows. Commission of Engineers, 1907 [7] (Box 5C, Folder 5)
    - Plan of tables and lockers, 1904 (Box 5C, Folder 5)
    - Plan of tables, etc. L. W. B., May 29, n.y. (Box 5C, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous drawings
    - Iron railing detail. C. E. Hodges (Box 5C, Folder 6)
    - Base for statue (Faith). C. E. Hodges (Box 5C, Folder 6)
    - Palo Alto Tree retaining wall (Box 5C, Folder 6)
    - “Mary Ann” (derrick?). Commission of Engineers, 1906 (Box 5C, Folder 6)
    - Derrick. Commission of Engineers, 1906 (Box 5C, Folder 6)
    - Fire proof room for oil transformers. S. M. 1908 (Box 5C, Folder 6)
  - Museum, C. E. Hodges drawings
    - Elevations, plans and details for rotunda. [14] (Box 5C, Folder 7)
  - Museum, A. J. Bain drawings
    - Elevations and plans, 1909-1910 [13] (Box 5C, Folder 8)
  - Museum, Percy & Hamilton drawings
    - Front elevation and traverse section [2] (Box 5C, Folder 9)
  - Natural Sciences Building [Quad], Henry A. Schulze drawings
    - Floor plans, 1899 [9] (Box 5C, Folder 10)
    - Cast iron railing for stairs, 1901 (Box 5C, Folder 10)
    - Details of grille on stair rails, 1902 (Box 5C, Folder 10)
  - Office for Charles Lathrop
    - Plan, with section for safe. (Box 5C, Folder 11)
    - Elevation of office fixtures. C. E. Hodges (Box 5C, Folder 11)
  - Pattern Shop
    - Building and roof plans and details. S. Moser, 1908 [6] (Box 5C, Folder 12)
  - Post Office
    - Plans and elevations. C. E. Hodges, ca. 1900 [6] (Box 5C, Folder 13)
  - Power House, proposed
    - Plans, elevations, details. C. E. Hodges [4] (Box 5C, Folder 14)
  - Power House, reconstruction
    - Elevations and plans. S. M., Commission of Engineers, 1908 [2] (Box 5C, Folder 15)
  - Quad, east/west gateway
    - Plan and elevation. C. E. Hodges [2] (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Quad, entrance tower
    - Plan, section, roof construction. Shepley, Rutan & Coolidge, 1888 [2] (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Quad, miscellaneous
    - Elevation, possibly of tower. Shepley, Rutan & Coolidge [2] (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Floor plan of one story building, S. E. end of outer quadrangle. C. E. Hodges (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Plan and elevation of drinking fountain. Shepley, Rutan & Coolidge (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Curbstone enclosing circles in quadrangle. Shepley, Rutan & Coolidge, 1889 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Quad, physics-psychology-philosophy building
    - Foundation, floor plans, and sections. Clinton Day [5] (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Restaurant
    - Front and side elevations. C. E. Hodges, ca. 1898 [2] (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Roble Gymnasium [first]
    - Elevations and plans. Shepley, Rutan & Coolidge [6] (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Plans and sections for an addition. A. J. Bain [5] (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - School House
    - Plans and elevations. C. E. Hodges [6] (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Stable, proposed alterations
    - Floor plans and front elevation. C. E. Hodges, 1904 [3] (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Street Car Waiting Station on campus
    - Front and side elevation. A. J. Bain, 1909 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Tiles
    - Plan of special tile. Commission of Engineers, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Plan of hip tile.. Commission of Engineers, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Wood Working Shop
    - Plans and elevations. C. E. Hodges [5] (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Workshop
    - Elevations and plans. Shepley, Rutan & Coolidge, 1889 and undated [6] (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Floor plan. H. B. Gale, 1891 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Plans for alteration into class rooms. C. E. Hodges [3] (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Cost details. C. M., 1907 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Plans for University residences and other buildings, including:
    - Residence to be built for the President, C. E. Hodges, 9 dwgs (Box 6)
    - Residence to be built for the President, Wolf and McKenzie, 8 dwgs (Box 6)
    - Delta Upsilon House, A. B. Clark, 11 dwgs (Box 6)
    - Club House, Chas. Austin, 1891, 6 dwgs (Box 6)
    - Phi Delta Theta, Henry Schulze, 1899, 9 dwgs (Box 6)
    - Club House, Shepley, Rutan and Coolidge, 6 dwgs (Box 6)
    - House for Dr. Durand, A. B. Clark, 1905, 6 dwgs (Box 6)
    - Sigma Alpha Epsilon House, Tharp & Holmes, 1901, 7 dwgs (Box 6)
    - Additions to the Chas. Lathrop house, C. E. Hodges, 21 dwgs (Box 6)
    - Residence of G. Richardson, Tobey architectect, 4 dwgs (Box 6)
    - Southwest corner of Quad (Geology), C. E. Hodges, 13 dwgs (Box 6)
    - Gridley Ranch, office building, 1914, 4 dwgs (Box 6)
    - Gridley Ranch, superintendant’s house, 1912, 7 dwgs (Box 6)
    - Gridley Ranch, mess house, 1912, 2 dwgs (Box 6)
    - Gridley Ranch, bunk house, 1912, 3 dwgs (Box 6)
    - Gridley Ranch, servant’s house, 1913, 3 dwgs (Box 6)
  - Specifications for furniture (circa 1910) (Box 7)
  - Specifications for furniture (circa 1910) (Box 8)
  - Specifications for heating system (circa 1890’s) (Box 9)
  - Specifications for heating system (circa 1890’s) (Box 10)
  - Specifications for campus drainage system, circa 1906 (Box 11)
  - Four Volumes: ledger for construction expenses to quad and campus, 1906
    - Indexed ledger for construction expenses, 1906 (Box 13)
    - General specifications for construction of Toyon and Encina Halls, 1922 (Box 13)
    - One page on water system, 1931 (Box 13)
  - Two Volumes: ledger on general sewage, roads, and topography, 1889
    - General description of the specifications of the residences and buildings on campus, no date (Box 14)
  - Oversize items:
    - Scrapbook of photographs and text from an exhibit on Stanford’s building plans, 1948 [unbound] (Box 15)
    - Scrapbook of clippings, 1944-1951 [brown binding] (Box 15)
    - Scrapbook of clippings, 1952-1953 [red binding] (Box 15)
- Stanford University Building Plans (negative prints), Accession ARCH-1991-123
  - Proposed semi-detached house #1 (C. E. Hodges-I900) W. Front Elev. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Proposed. semi-detached house #1 - Foundation Plan (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Proposed semi-detached house #1 - First floor Plan (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Proposed. semi-detached house #1 - Second Floor Plan (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Proposed semi-detached house #1 - Roof Plan (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Proposed semi-detached house #3 - Front Elevation (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Proposed semi-detached house #3 - Secondary Front Elevation (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Proposed. semi-detached house #3 - Foundation Plan (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Proposed semi-detached house #3 - First floor Plan (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Proposed. semi-detached house #3 - Second floor Plan (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Proposed semi-detached house #3 - Roof Plan (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Proposed semi-detached house #2 - Front Elevation (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Proposed semi-detached house #2 - Secondary Front Elevation (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Proposed. semi-detached house #2 - Foundation Plan (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Proposed semi-detached house #2 - First floor Plan (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Proposed. semi-detached house #2 - Second floor Plan (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Proposed semi-detached house #2 - Roof Plan (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Cottage - Front & Side Elevations (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Cottage - Foundation, Roof & Attic Plans (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Cottage - First & Second floor Plans (Box 1, Folder 20)